大西洋帝国
第五季 第二集
联邦探员
Federal agents.
联邦探员 不许动
Federal agents. Don't move.
芝加哥
把角落那帮废材弄出来
Get the rats out of those corners.
-都赶出来  -是
-Flush 'em out. - Yes,sir.
钱都放桌子上
Cash on the table.
这就对了
That's right.
弟兄们 好好审问他们
Give 'em the third degree,boys.
该死
Fuck.
纳吉 你确定吗 真不吃点东西
You sure,Nuck? Nothing to eat?
约翰 不用了 谢谢
Thank you,John,no.
谢谢
Grazie.
来杯茴香酒吧
Anisette?
-约翰  -给客人而已
-John. -For our guest.
从那不勒斯偷偷弄来的
Snuck it back from Naples.
那么难得 来点吧
Well,in that case.
什么风把你吹来纽约了
So,what brings you to New York?
我也想问你这个问题
I was about to ask you the same thing.
我家在这 在这退休也是理所当然
I'm from here. Figured might as well retire here.
约翰 你气色不错 很放松
You look good,John. Relaxed.
还是不太能吞咽
I still can't swallow right.
一小块饼干就有可能让我一命呜呼
A few crumbs from a biscotto'll send me into a choking fit.
总得付出点代价的
Small price to pay.
问题是不知道为何而付出这代价呀
If only I knew what I was paying for.
我一直觉得是为班宁吧
I'd always assumed O'Banion.
离家稍近点
A little closer to home.
卡蓬(美国黑手党老大)找你了吗
Capone moved on you?
不管所为何事 确实是收到这个风声了
Let's just say whoever it was, I got the message.
参与这事的几个人
Most fellas in this business,
都直接去阎王爷那报道了
they get their retirement papers straight from the Grim fucking Reaper.
科洛西莫 罗思坦
Colosimo,Rothstein,
马塞里亚
Masseria.
明天是他的下葬仪式
Got his wake tomorrow.
老大乔 整个墓地里最有钱的人
Joe the Boss. Richest man in the cemetery.
我会出席葬礼 假情假意一下
I'll show up, pretend to say a prayer,
然后回家 听鲁迪瓦利的歌
then I'll come home and listen to Rudy Vallee.
日子过得真逍遥啊
Pleasant evening.
纳吉 我心满意足了
I got everything I need,Nucky.
吃得饱 看看电影 喂喂鸟
I eat,go to pictures, feed the birds.
我终于脱离那烂摊子了 绝不回头了
I walked away from that other shit and I never looked back.
那估计你也不知道是谁要买我的命吧
Then I suppose you'd have no opinion on who tried to have me clipped.
什么 什么时候的事
What? When was this?
就在哈瓦那(古巴城市) 两天前
Havana. Two days ago.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
事发之前 我还在咖啡店遇见了梅耶 兰斯基
I ran into Meyer Lansky at a cafe before it happened.
他经常去那边
He's down there all the time.
-为何  -谁知道呢
-What for? - Who knows?
逃避他老婆吧
Get away from his wife.
先是马塞里亚 现在是我
Masseria,then me.
相隔不到24小时
Within 24 hours.
要我说 我认为那犹太人是马拉暂罗派来的
Ask me,the little kike's taking orders from Maranzano.
那就找他问清楚 面对面好好谈谈
Sit down with him direct. Look him right in the eye.
-马拉暂罗吗  -我可以帮你搭线 如果你想的话
-Maranzano? - I'll broker if you want.
帮你约他
Be your go-between.
这年复一年的
Year in,year out,
物是人非了 却始终围着一个问题打转
different dogs, same fucking bone.
你还要我说几次啊
Well,how many times you need to hear it?
由天命 退休颐养天年吧
Take the hint and retire already.
耶和华啊 请守护你的孩子们
O Lord,who watches over children
不管是此生 抑或是来世
in this present life and the world to come,
让他们在安息中
bringing them to live with the spirits
得到永生
of the divine rest,
请接收你的小仆人苏珊
receive in peace the soul
让她的灵魂收获安宁
of your little servant Susan.
-阿门  -阿门
-Amen. -Amen.
该死的高烧
Damn heat.
他们为何还没来
Why haven't they come?
我一小时前就通知殡仪馆的人了
I sent a message for the undertaker hours ago.
快帮你们的姐妹祈祷吧
Say a prayer for your sister.
快 祈祷吧
Go... go on.
她死了
Is she dead?
别哭
Hush yourself now.
亲爱的 她去见耶稣了
She's with Jesus now,dear.
没事的
It's going to be all right.
带他出去
Take him outside.
出去 该死的 你也该干嘛干嘛去
Go,God damn it, and get to your work.
我们没钱了吗 所以他们才不来 是吗
Have we no money? Is that why they haven't come?
罐子里还有一块钱
There was a dollar in the tin.
-让我来解决  -你是不是又拿去买酒了
-Leave me be. -Did you drink it away?
-你说啊  -她也是我的孩子
-Just tell me that. -She's my child,too.
想到她要葬在公共墓地我就难过
The thought of her in potter's field.
不可能
There'll be none of that.
闭嘴
Quiet now.
把她埋在院子里吧
She'll rest in the yard
离家近
so she's close.
纽约
抱歉 很紧张
Sorry. Nerves.
事实自证
Res ipsa loquitur.
汤普森先生
Mr. Thompson?
在 谢谢
Yes. Thank you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
威廉 汤普森
William Thompson.
罗伯特 霍奇 欢迎
Robert Hodge. Welcome.
-外面很多人吗  -有点
-Is it crowded out there? -A little bit.
假设
Hypothetical...
你是助理检控官
you're an assistant US Attorney,
你要起诉一个人 假设他叫贝克吧
you're prosecuting a fella, let's call him Baker.
他因为偷窃被捕
Now,this Baker's been arrested for petty theft,
由于第二天一早 就要放人了
due to be released the next morning.
当晚 一个警探来电
That night,a detective calls,
说这个人就是俄亥俄州
says he's certain this is the same Baker who's a stickup artist
一系列抢劫案的劫匪
from Ohio wanted for a string of robberies.
他要你"不小心"遗失犯人的释放文件
What he needs is for you to misplace Baker's paperwork
好扣押他直到扬斯敦的逮捕文件到达
till the file arrives from Youngstown in two more days.
如果你不这样做 犯人就会被释放 他就有可能潜逃了
If you don't and Baker's released, chances are he'll flee.
你会做吗
Well?
我不会做
I can't do it.
他只不过被扣押多一会
So he cools his heels awhile.
在牢房里多呆两天而已
Three squares and a cot.
对谁都不是坏事
That's not a bad deal for anyone nowadays.
-这是违反职业道德的  -他可是个累犯
-It's unethical,sir. -He's an ex-jailbird.
他还杀了一个铁路工人
He killed a railway clerk.
他抛弃了他的妻子和六个孩子
He left a wife and six kids
而你只需帮警察一点小忙而已 这都不行吗
and you can't do the police a simple favor?
法律是盾牌 不是利剑
The law is a shield, sir,not a sword.
大西洋城 圣灵高中
Holy Spirit High School, Atlantic City.
在费城实习 纽约的圣约翰律师事务所任过职
Then Temple in Philadelphia and St. John's Law in New York.
大西洋城
Atlantic City.
你该不会跟纳吉 汤普森是一家的吧
I don't suppose you're related to Nucky Thompson.
他是我父亲的兄弟
He's my father's brother.
这个关系通常被定义为叔侄关系
That relationship is usually classified as uncle.
先生 家人是无法选择的
Well,you don't get to choose your relatives,sir.
确实
No.
但有些人 是可以选择他们的职员的
But some of us get to choose our staff members.
-霍奇先生 我...  -谢谢你来面试
-Mr. Hodge,I... -Thank you for coming in.
有必要的话 我会跟着他
I'd tail him myself if I had to.
-什么  -贝克 那个小偷
-What? -Baker,your stickup man.
我会遵循法律条文 释放他
I'd make sure he was released in accordance with the law,
但我不会让他离开我的视线范围
but I wouldn't let him out of my sight
直到扬斯敦的逮捕令下来
until the file arrived from Youngstown.
先生 我很想成为一个检控官
I want to be a prosecutor,sir.
我想把罪犯都送进监狱
I want to put criminals in jail.
不能一竹篙打死一船人
The ones who divide families.
我看着我父亲死去
I've lost my own father,
不知多少次 听着我母亲哭到睡去
heard my mother cry herself to sleep more times than I can count.
我清楚知道犯罪活动给人带来的痛苦
I know the way crime eats you out from the inside.
我有切身体验 我对此非常痛恨
I know it and I hate it.
先生 请给我个机会
Give me a chance,sir. Please?
让我尽我一生做点好事
Let me do something good with my life.
"全名公敌" "小凯撒"(黑帮犯罪电影) 都看过了吗
"Public Enemy," "Little Caesar," have you seen either of those?
都是喜剧 很好笑
Comedies. Good for a chuckle.
迈克呢
Where's Mike?!
我猜他在来的路上
He's on his way,I guess.
你猜 给我去找
You guess? Go fucking find him.
-多弗吗  -该死的安吉洛在哪
-Dove? -Where the fuck is D'Angelo?
-安吉洛在哪  -该死的安吉洛在哪
-Where's D'Angelo? -Where the fuck is D'Angelo?
-安吉洛在哪  -有个放映员来了
-Where's D'Angelo? -Had a projectionist come over,
带他来见我们
show 'em to me and the boys.
拉尔菲 你觉得怎么样
Hey,Ralphie,what do you think?
单褶还是双褶
Single pleats or double?
双啊 得给"肠"多点新鲜空气嘛
Double. Give the saus each a little breathing room.
-你听到了 一打  -双褶
-You heard him. A dozen pair. -Double pleats.
你给自己拍过照吗
Would you ever do a picture yourself?
为什么要拍 我已经出名了
What for? I'm already famous.
该死的迈克呢
Where the fuck's Mike?!
我在找 阿尔 我在找
I'm on it,Al. I'm on it.
-我们在找 阿尔 我们在找  -该死的迈克呢
-We're on it,Al. We're on it. -Where the fuck's Mike?!
-又要干什么  -好莱坞的"多样性"
-What's this for again? -"Variety" in Hollywood.
呼叫迈克'安吉洛 呼叫迈克'安吉洛
Paging Mike D'Angelo. Paging Mike D'Angelo!
马上到 阿尔 马上到
In a jiffy,Al. In a jiffy.
他正朝大厅走来 阿尔
He's coming down the hall now,Al.
Hey,he's coming down the hall now,Al.
-2英寸袖口  -以你的身高 1寸半...
-Two-inch cuffs. -At your height,an inch a half is...
2英寸
two inches.
-收到许多影迷来信吗  -迈克到了 阿尔
-Get a lot of fan mail? - Here's Mike,Al.
12秒时间 迈克
12 seconds with the big boy,Mike.
别惹他激动
Don't get him agitated.
迈克 你去哪了 一直在找你
Mike,where you been? Been asking for you.
老板 有什么事
What's on your mind,boss?
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry,sorry.
-这段对话不能记录  -为什么 好
-This is off the record. -Why,sure.
-很自然  -拉尔菲 我找迈克干什么
-Naturally. -Ralphie,what I want Mike for?
我不知道 阿尔 你没说
I don't know,Al. You didn't say.
天哪 事太多了
Jesus,I got a lot on my mind.
-现在你问我吧  -其实 阿尔 我得和你谈谈
-Now,you gotta ask me. -Actually,Al,I need to talk to you.
昨晚 斯普林格6号 联邦探员
Last night, 6th and Springer,feds.
什么 情况如果
What? How bad?
600瓶加拿大俱乐部加威酒
600 cases Canadian Club.
-有现金吗  -不到2万美金
-Any cash? -Just shy of 20 grand.
天哪 走开 帕迪
Jesus! Back off,Puddy!
-滚开 赶紧走  -好
-Take a hike. Shoo,come on. -All right.
-让他滚  -抱歉
-Get him outta here. -Apologies!
-滚 滚开  -抱歉
-Get outta here. Take a hike. -Sorry.
斯普林格6号 谁的地盘
6th and Springer. Whose territory is that?
米勒和另一个人
Mueller and the other one.
大西洋城
Atlantic City.
他说自己一直有掏钱
He says he's been making his payoffs,
但这个探员 管事的那个 说从来没见过
but this fed,the one in charge, says he never saw him before.
关阿尔什么事
How's that Al's problem?
无关
It ain't.
我只是想告诉他一声
I just,you know, want to make him aware.
我知道了
I'm aware.
那些小丑欠我2万
Those clowns owe me 20 grand.
让米勒去找钱
Tell Mueller he finds the dough
否则打烂他的老二
or I'll sell his balls for fucking scrap!
你刚才想告诉我影迷的来信
You were telling me about your fan mail.
对 来自世界各地的信
Sure. Comes in from all over the world.
都想和我交流
People looking to make a touch.
-柏林  -看到没
-Berlin. -See?
德国佬都知道我是王子
Even the Krauts know what a prince I am.
-请问几楼  -9楼
-Floor,please? -Nine.
他生气了吗
Was he upset?
阿尔 不 他还放声大笑呢
Al? No. He had a big laugh of it.
-那就是...  -他当然生气了 你这头蠢驴
-Well,that's a rel... -Of course he was upset, you fucking blockhead.
2万美金 你以为那是小钱吗
20 grand,you think that's peanuts?
-安吉洛先生 我...  -14楼
-Mr. D'Angelo,I... -14th floor.
12楼
12th,skip.
换到套房了
Switching to a suite.
12楼
12th floor.
日安
Have a good day.
你要归还那笔钱
You're gonna replace that dough.
一毛都不能少 明白吗
Every last cent. You understand?
-那怎么可能  -现在还给我还嘴
-How am I supposed to do that? -You gonna give me lip now?
-不 先生  -给我处理好
-No,sir. -Figure it the fuck out.
肯定是你身边的人泄密了
Got to be something rattling around that giant coconut of yours.
9楼
Ninth floor.
给你24小时 米勒
You got 24 hours,Mueller.
下去
Going down.
怎样
Well?
那他骂你做什么
What's he hocking you for?
你为我工作 我替你担着
You work for me, so I'm getting the blame.
你想从我这里得到什么
What do you want from me?
幸亏我没有被抓住
I was lucky I wasn't pinched myself.
-我们不得不对此负责  -我跟他说了
-We have to answer for this. -I told him what happened.
童子军一样的联邦探员想成名
Some Boy Scout fed trying to make a name for himself.
你聋了吗 安吉洛先生不在乎
Are you deaf? Mr. D'Angelo does not care.
卡波尼先生要钱
Mr. Capone wants his money.
-那米勒先生可以去...  -5楼
-And Mr. Mueller can go f... -Fifth floor.
茶室 谢谢
Tearoom,please.
看看我的黛西
Oh,say hello to my Daisy.
Say hello to my Daisy.
你好 黛西
Hello,Daisy.
就是这样
Yeah. There you go.
是不是很好吗
Oh,isn't that nice?
好
Yes.
3楼 茶室
Third floor. Tearoom.
-谢谢  -谢谢
-Thank you. -Thank you.
该死的钱
Goddamn fucking money.
我会要回来的 好吗
I'll get it back,okay?
你满口承诺 是吗
You're chock-full of promises,aren't you?
我说过我来处理
I said I'd take care of it.
你连自己都顾不了
You can barely take care of yourself.
对了 你好臭
You reek,by the way.
尿骚味
Of urine.
大厅已到
Lobby.
去见"大老板"
Going to see the big fella.
我们会去萨拉托加度夏
We would summer in Saratoga.
就在马丁的工厂还在时
This was when Martin still had the factory.
我会和孩子们一同起床 打开房门
I'd go up with the children and open the house.
马丁会留下来 处理自己的私情
And Martin would stay in the city and tend to his affairs.
我说的就是字面意思
And I do mean that literally.
他很大张旗鼓吗
Was he that brazen?
若非细心注意 不会发现
Oh,nothing if not discreet.
萨拉托加的夏季非常美妙
And the season in Saratoga was always very gracious.
我们更喜欢大西洋城
We preferred Atlantic City.
我丈夫在那有"小家"...
My husband had family there,so...
欢迎与纳丁 圣 克莱尔夫人
And now it's time for "The Good Listener"
共同收听"暗诉倾听"
with Mrs. Nadine St. Clair.
亲爱的朋友们
Hello,dear friends.
感谢大家的收听
Thank you for joining me today.
我更喜欢"知心阿姨" 你呢
Oh,I do love a bit of the agony aunt,don't you?
在某些日子
In these uncertain times,
你是否突然好奇有人
wouldn't you like to know there's someone
能否理解你的负担
who understands our burdens?
但朋友们 我希望大家知道
But,dear friends,I hope you realize
我会一直伴在大家左右
you can always talk to me.
第一封信来自莫里斯敦的JW
Our first letter comes from J.W. in Morristown.
她的故事令人心碎
She relates a heartbreaking tale.
意外怀孕
Unwanted pregnancy.
"亲爱的圣 克莱尔夫人
"Dear Mrs. St. Clair,
这三年来 我的未婚夫
for the last three years my fiancé
承诺说他母亲一过世
has promised that as soon as his mother passed on,
就会给我名分"...
he would do right by me and"...
你干嘛关掉
Why did you do that?
它会带来不好的氛围
It doesn't create a conducive atmosphere.
我在听呢
I was listening.
你可以在客厅里听
Well,you can listen in the parlor.
-没事的  -真的没事吧
-It's all right. -Isn't it all right?
我还想听 真的很想听
I'd like to listen. I'd like to listen.
我想听纳丁 圣 克莱尔讲话
I'd like to listen to Nadine St. Clair.
我...想听
I... I want to.
总是这么吵吗
Always this noisy?
-进步的声音  -一整栋复式楼层
-Sound of progress. -Got a whole complex planned.
洛克菲勒中心
Rockefeller Center.
建一间神社对谁都没有影响
Nothing wrong with building a shrine to oneself.
钱不就是这个用处吗
Isn't that what money's for?
劳埃德议员表示遗憾
Your Senator Lloyd sends his regrets.
他有事在华盛顿耽搁了
He's been detained down in Washington.
若大家不介意 我还是想占用一些时间
Well,if you don't mind,I'd like a few moments of your time anyway.
你想干什么
And why exactly should you have it?
作为新成立的五月花号
Because as the board members
粮食公司董事会成员
of the newly formed Mayflower Grain Corporation,
在我来看 局势相当明显
it's fairly obvious,to me at least,
各位准备进军酒精行业
that you gentlemen are poised to enter the liquor business.
有吗
Is that so?
除非是我多心了 各位觉得麦片要比
Unless I'm wrong and there's more potential
大麦和啤酒花更有潜力
in Wheatena than in barley and hops.
汤普森先生 为了拉拢议员
We agreed to meet,Mr. Thompson,
我们才同意会面
as an accommodation to the senator.
由于你们的特殊关系
Owing to your special relationship.
但为了便与讨论
But let's suppose for the moment,
可以假设你是对的
for the sake of argument,that you're right
我们的确不是太关注早餐麦片
and breakfast cereal is only half our concern.
但又为何要听你的呢
Why should we listen to you?
因为我最近去了哈瓦那
As a result of my recent trip to Havana,
还获得了巴卡第朗姆酒
I've secured exclusive North American
北美独家发行权
distribution rights for Bacardi Rum.
签署法律条文后 马上进行销售
In the event the sale of their product once again becomes legal.
我提议合伙经营
I propose we pool our resources,
大家成为伙伴关系
enter into a partnership.
以我的经验和技术
With my experience and know-how,
我们可以建立一个基地
we can build an infrastructure
逐步扩大占有市场....
ready to distribute alcohol throughout...
-什么经验  -你说什么
-What experience? -Beg pardon?
你说的是什么经验
To what experience are you referring?
我涉猎过许多领域
My background is quite varied.
可以详细介绍一下吗
Would you care to elaborate?
你要是怀疑我的品行 劳埃德议员...
If there's any question of my integrity,Senator Lloyd...
我们只想知道你进军酒水业的资格 请详述
We're simply asking what qualifies you to be in the liquor business.Specifically.
我的资格就是过去的11年间
What qualifies me is that for the past 11 years
我是美国最成功的酒水走私商
I have been one of the most successful bootleggers in the country.
我明白了
Oh,I see.
你假装不知道 有什么很好的理由吗
Is there a reason you wanted to pretend as if you didn't know?
我们更喜欢摆在台面上说话
We prefer putting our cards on the table.
-这样才能达成共识  -好的
-Just so we're all on the same page. - Fine.
那次危机对我的打击很大 先生们
The crash hit me hard as anyone,gentlemen.
我没法提供资金来操作
I can't finance an operation like I have in mind on my own.
这是本末倒置
You're putting the cart before the horse.
你得向我们保证 汤普森先生
We need assurances,Mr. Thompson,
禁酒令真的会撤销
that repeal actually is on the horizon.
若那次集会表明了一件事
A half million women seem to think so,
那就是50万的女性都相信
if that rally was any indication.
女性改革 还是什么的
Women For Reform,or whatever they call themselves.
想要实现和最终实现
Wanting something and achieving it
是有天差地别的
are two very different things.
但二者一般会接连发生
Though one naturally follows the other.
我们赌的是同一件事 各位
We're betting on the same thing,boys.
禁酒令真的会撤销
That repeal is going to happen.
也许是真的 但没有议员...
That may be true,but without the senator...
我会劝议员回心转意
I'll get the senator back onboard.
我很确定
I'm fairly certain
我们都知道这是不可能的事
we both know that's not gonna happen.
但真的很感谢你能来
We do appreciate your coming in,however.
我也曾做过这生意 知道吗
I made the same deal,you know.
什么
Excuse me?
穿越大西洋
Across the pond.
等这国家的人想通后 进口杜瓦瓶
To import Dewar's when the country returns to its senses.
还有酩悦香槟
Moet Champagne as well.
这想法很棒
Great minds,I suppose.
您结婚了吗 汤普森先生
Married,Mr. Thompson?
理论上是 情况很复杂
Technically. It's complicated.
偷腥是人之常情
Well,affairs of the heart always are.
所以你的合伙人们
So your partners,
那只是审批程序
was that just a vetting process
还是我该选择其它出口
or should I find some other doorway to darken?
你这样的人让他们很害怕
A man like you frightens them.
这些人是社会精英 不会大吼大叫
These are Brahmins,not brawlers.
你倒没有很慌乱
Well,you don't seem particularly rattled.
大西洋帝国
Atlantic City.
下次登门拜访时会联系您
I'll ring you up next time I visit.
汤普森先生
Mr. Thompson.
肯尼迪先生
Mr. Kennedy.
多里奥传信说 马拉暂罗想见你
Torrio sent word. Maranzano wants to meet.
下午好 女士们
Ah,afternoon,my ladies.
-你们的皇家车夫正在等候  -真是豪华
-Your royal coachman awaits. -Oh,how regal.
#暮色时分唱支歌#
#Just a song at twilight#
#现已是天色昏暗#
# When the lights are low#
#黑影摇曳#
#And the flickering shadows#
#轻轻的来往#
#Softly come and go..#
还有小夜曲
And a serenade as well.
#也许是身心疲惫#
#Though the heart be weary#
#度过冗长一天#
#Sad the day and long#
#但在这暮色之下#
#Still to us at twilight...#
看看 这是谁
Well,look who it is.
没有你 地球都不转了
The linchpin of the entire organization.
对不起 我迟到了 先生
Sorry I'm tardy,sir.
确实是
So you are. So you are.
我很担心
I was worried sick.
是的 先生
Yes,sir.
其实 卢...
Actually,Lou...
我们这是在做生意 孩子
We're running a business,boy.
你是其中的关键
You're a critical part of the operation.
你不能想来就来 想走就走
You can't just come and go willy-nilly.
-不是的 先生  -沙子会自己变没吗
-No,sir. - You think that sand will sweep itself?
为什么 你不出现 这里都一片混乱了
Why,you don't show up,this whole place descends into chaos.
整个酒店都前途未卜
The very future of this hotel hanging in the balance.
-也许...  -我妹过世了
- Maybe... -My sister passed.
-什么  -我妹 先生
-What? - My sister,sir.
她昨晚死去了
She died last night
当时我们都在睡觉
while we were sleeping.
有什么下葬仪式 要做弥撒吗
Are there services? A mass?
-我想去表示一下敬意  -没有 先生
-I'd like to pay my respects. -No,sir.
神父主持最后的仪式 我们想把她葬在家里
The Father came for last rites,but we're burying her at home.
你该送点什么东西
You should send something.
为什么 他家老爷子觉得我很坏
What for? Kid's old man thinks I'm a devil.
他也是选民 不是吗
He votes,don't he?
真是悲剧 失去妹妹
A tragedy,losing a sister.
好了 那就去到工作中找安慰吧
All right,then,go on. Find solace in your work.
爸爸
Say,Dad.
什么
What is it?
为什么云朵能漂浮在空中
Why do clouds just float in the sky?
这是笑话吗
Is this a joke?
是为科学课做准备
It's for science class.
去问你母亲
Go ask your mother.
她让我来问你
She said to ask you.
我很忙 切斯特 你看得见 不是吗
I'm busy,Chester.You can see that,can't you?
云朵漂浮...
Clouds float...
是因为大气
because of the atmosphere.
-可是...  -别问了 上楼去
-But... -Shoo! Upstairs.
你正在收听的是"弗莱施曼的酵母时间"(19世纪30年代著名音乐节目)
You are listening to "Fleischmann's Yeast Hour"
爸爸说 是因为大气
Dad says on account of atmosphere.
很好
Good.
去完成作业
Finish your homework.
抽烟完全不淑女
That is a thoroughly unladylike habit.
-你去工作  -是的
-You are working? -Yes.
你啥时候回来
When you will be home?
我啥时候回来
When will I be home?
-我何时回来  -我就是这么说的
-When will I be home? -This is what I say.
不 你说的是"你啥时候回来" 完全不一样...
No, what you said was,"When you will be home?" which is entirely...
有何区别
What is difference?
区别在于 我在教孩子们说标准英语
Difference is I'm trying to raise our children to speak proper English.
顺便问问 阿比盖尔在哪
Where is Abigail, by the way?
女童军在开会
At her meeting for the Girl Scouts.
我要迟到了
I'll be late.
务必让切斯特祈祷
See that Chester says his prayers.
宇宙最喜欢
The universe loves nothing so much
改变现有事物
as to change things which are
并创造类似的新事物
and to make new things like them.
汤普森先生 你信奉马可 奥里利乌斯(西方哲学家)的哲学吗
You're a student of Marcus Aurelius, Mr. Thompson?
我更支持本 富兰克林(美国著名的政治家 科学家)
I'm more of a Ben Franklin man myself.
"聚沙可以成塔 积水可以成河"
"A penny saved is a penny earned."
类似的哲学
That sort of thing.
马塞里亚
Masseria,
乔老大
Joe the Boss,
很顽固
he was stubborn.
非常倔
Like a mule.
而倔强的他 只懂得来硬的
And like a mule, he only understood the switch.
暴力
Violence.
这些 你都非常了解
But you know this all too well.
我跟马拉暂罗先生讲了你的事情
I brought Mr. Maranzano up to speed with your history.
我们确实有过冲突
It's true we had our difficulties.
我努力跟这家伙理论 不知多少次了
How many times I try to reason with the man?
结果呢
And for what?
结果无效
A goose egg.
为何要杀我
So why try to kill me?
我没有
This I did not do.
事发前一天 我在古巴看到了他的伙伴
I saw his partner down in Cuba the day before it happened.
我和迈耶几个月没说过话了
Meyer and I haven't even spoke to each other in months.
闹翻了
A falling out?
关系可破裂 友谊可终结
People drift. Friendships end.
可交新朋友
And new ones are forged.
也可易主
Allegiances change as well.
人的价值取决于野心
A man's worth is no greater than his ambitions.
托尼诺是个好孩子
He's a good boy,Tonino.
汤普森先生
Mr. Thompson.
我和兰斯基先生只有一面之缘
Mr. Lansky I've met only once.
没有深度交流
We have no intercourse whatsoever.
只有西西里人
Sicilians only.
你和迈耶各有千秋
Meyer's got his thing, you got yours.
我们想要...
What we do here...
不用担心我们
Concerns no one but us.
汤普森先生 你不用怕我
You have nothing to fear from me, Mr. Thompson.
谁说我害怕了
Who said I was afraid?
我该不该信他
So do I believe him or not?
无论如何 你要相信这事让你脱离困境
Believe whatever it is gets you out of this mess.
古兹克路的最后一站
It's the last stop on Guzik's route.
至少有两万美元
Got to be 20 grand in that speak at least.
等他出来再动手
When he comes out, we make our move.
相信我 他不会挣扎
Trust me, he won't put up a fight.
你们分开多久了
You've been apart how long?
什么
What?
你和你妻子
From your wife.
不知道 天啊
I don't know. Jesus.
差不多六年了
Six years or so.
我们隔三差五还约见
I mean, we arrange to see each other now and again,
但很艰难
but it's hard.
你心里还有她
You still care for her.
当然 当然
Of course. Sure.
我只惦记她和孩子
All I think about are her and the kids.
有时 我觉得 恨人比爱人
Sometimes I find it easier to despise someone
要容易
than to love them.
这家伙在哪
The fuck is this guy?
-悠着点  -把枪给我
-Whoa,whoa. Easy! -Give me the fucking gun.
冷静 谁都别受伤
Steady now and no one gets hurt.
伙计 知道你在抢谁吗
You know who you're robbing, pal?
彼得 付保罗的钱
Peter. To pay Paul.
怎么回事
What the fuck?
我说了 冷静
I said steady.
冷静
Steady.
我说...
I said...
我说冷静 天啊...
I said steady, God...
-我腿不行了  -见鬼
-I can't move my legs. -Fuck!
-乔伊 乔伊  -我要挂了 杰克
-Joey! Joey! -I'm gonna fucking die, Jack!
-该死的 走  -我的腿 见鬼
-Fuck! Let's go. -My legs! My fucking legs!
你死定了 混蛋
You're dead, you son of a bitch!
-快 我的腿  -那是阿尔 卡蓬的钱
-Come on. My legs. -That's Al Capone's money.
-该死的 开枪打我 我快挂了  -乔伊
-He fucking shot me. I'm fucking dying. -Joey!
别 别...
No, don't shoo...
走
Let's go!
为何总是一团糟
Why must it always be pandemonium?
你听过那谜语吗
You ever hear that riddle,
旅者和两个部落成员
the traveler and the two tribesmen?
一个总撒谎 另一个总说真话
One always lies, the other always tells the truth.
我沉默 他们又来找我
I lay down, they come after me again.
我回击...
I fight back...
今天我碰到了一个爱尔兰人
I met a man today,an Irishman.
百万富翁 已婚
Millions of dollars,married,
涉猎很多不同的领域
has his fingers in a dozen different pies.
赚的是黑心钱吗
Think he's wading through blood to make a buck?
有时候 因为你已选择
You get to the point where you
必须坚持下去
have to live with the choices you've made.
不管是好是坏
The good ones and the bad.
我同意
And I accept that.
我就快成功了 该死 那么近
I'm right there. This fucking close.
酒的交易一旦成了 我就会很富
This liquor deal comes through and I'm golden.
现在问题是希望能活到那一天
Then the trick's to stay alive long enough to cash out.
你根本就不知道我在说什么 是吧
You haven't the slightest idea what I'm talking about,do you?
是
Sí.
是知道 还是不知道
Sí,you do,or sí,you don't?
有何区别
What's the difference?
如果你喝一杯 就会显得有道理多了
If you'd have a drink, I'd make a lot more sense.
到底有没有要说的
Do you have anything to say at all?
我杀他们 我不杀他们
I kill them,I don't kill them.
听你吩咐
Whatever you say.
节奏男孩的宾 克鲁斯拜(歌手)
Bing Crosby of the Rhythm Boys
最后一集是合唱 "莫名其妙"
gave you the chorus in the last selection,"Out of Nowhere."
格斯 安海姆和大使
Gus Arnheim and his Ambassadors
继续出席椰林歌舞会
at the Cocoanut Grove continues.
90分钟前就离开了
Left almost 90 minutes ago.
扬克斯路吗
By way of Yonkers?
也许马拉暂罗派他去买炸甜甜圈了
Maranzano probably sent him for crullers.
什么 托尼诺 也许他和甜甜圈做爱去了
Who,Tonino? He'd probably fuck that up,too.
笨蛋已经来了
The schmuck's already here.
该死 你
The fuck were you?
我来早了 想磨扣子
I was here early. I figured I'd get my knob polished.
-你14岁吗  -我们一直在下面等
-What are you,14? -We're down here waiting.
抱歉 就是 你们知道的
I'm sorry. It's just,you know.
怎么还不走
You posing for animal crackers?
他还没给我小费
He ain't tipped me yet.
去散步
Take a walk.
马克西姆怎么说
What's the word on Maranzano?
他怀疑了吗
Is he suspicious?
他就那样 胆战心惊 时刻警惕
You know how he is. Plays it close to the vest.
下车的时候 他说什么了吗
Did he say anything when you dropped him off?
他说了很多乱七八糟的 马卡斯 波罗
He says a lot of shit. Marcus Polo.
该死 谁知道他在说什么
Who the fuck knows what he's talking about?
他认为你们意见不和 离开了
You ask me,he believes you fellas are on the outs.
什么依据
Based on what?
没什么 不知道 个人之见
Nothing. I don't know. My opinion.
-我可不喜欢 查理  -放松
-I don't like this,Charlie. -Relax.
-我们是乡下人  -如此肯定 真好
-We're jake. -How nice you're so sure.
你非得找汤普森谈谈
You had to talk to Thompson?
-在该死的哈瓦那(古巴城市)  -我该怎么做
-Down in fucking Havana. -What should I have done?
天啊 也许别跟他说了
Gee,maybe not fucking talk to him?
他看到我了 本尼 最好面对
He saw me,Benny. Better to face it head-on.
把你的鼻子伸到不该去的地方
做个好孩子
别烦人们
这难道也算过分吗
该死的神经病
Hey,fuck you, you fucking screwball!
够了
Enough.
马拉暂罗以为 迈耶是自己要干掉汤普森
As far as Maranzano knows,Meyer took it on himself to ice Thompson.
谁知道那该死的外国佬怎么想的
Who knows what that fucking greaseball thinks?
我说我们马上行动 把他杀了
I say we move now. Just take him the fuck out.
太快了 没人支持我们
It's too soon. We don't got the support.
支持 我们是谁 政客吗
Support? What are we, politicians?
什么 托尼诺
What,Tonino?
王子街 我接管
Prince Street. Me taking over.
我做到了 你说过会考虑
I did the thing,you said you'd think about it.
马塞里亚还没死呢
Masseria ain't even in the fucking ground yet.
我知道 只是提醒一下
I know. I'm just reminding you.
回楼上去 找人上床去
Go back upstairs. Get yourself a rim job.
对我发什么火
What are you sore at me for?
一会儿聊 好吗
We'll catch up later,okay?
他是个真正的笨蛋
He's a real fucking schnorrer,this one.
对 他没事
Yeah,he's all right.
跟吉普 罗塞蒂去说吧
Tell it to Gyp Rosetti.
怎么回事
What's this now?
伊桑
Ethan.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我来问候你
I've come to pay my respects to you,
还有你的妻子
your wife.
确实很悲伤
It's a terrible blow.
她不在
She's not here.
你孩子都告诉我了
Your boy told me what happened.
青天化日下 白白失去一个无辜的孩子
Is there anything worse under God's blue heaven
真是太糟糕了
than the loss of an innocent child?
那是什么
What's that?
让你的女儿体面下葬
To give your daughter a proper burial.
你以为能收买我两次吗
Think you can buy me twice?
那是公平交易 伊桑
It was a fair deal,Ethan.
没人强迫你卖掉土地
No one forced you to sell that land.
今天放假 孩子 和你的家人在一起
Take the day,boy. Be with your family.
谢谢 先生 但没什么区别 更愿意干活
Thank you,sir,but if it's all the same, I'd rather come to work.
-别激动  -爸
-Easy there. -Pa.
该死 你剥夺了我所有的财产
You get the hell off my property.
我没有你认为的那么坏 伊桑
I'm not the monster that you think I am,Ethan.
他怎么样 霍奇
What's he like? Hodge?
他爽快
Well,he's direct,
坚强 热心
tough,earnest.
让我想起了泰迪 罗斯福(美国第26任总统)
Sort of reminded me of Teddy Roosevelt.
希望他不用手杖
Without the big stick,I hope.
面试时 他们会问你这些问题
In the interview they ask you these questions,
看你是不是正直
try to test your integrity.
为了抓人你会违法吗
Would you ever break the law to get a conviction?
就那些事
That type of thing.
有提到我吗
My name come up?
什么
Excuse me?
面试的时候
During the interview.
没有
No.
当然没有
'Course not.
提到了我也不会以此为耻
I wouldn't be ashamed if it did.
你很高尚
Well,that's very noble,
但你要为将来考虑
but you've got a future to think about.
威廉 汤普森
William H. Thompson,
最高法院首席法官
Chief Justice of the Supreme Court.
只要你不是新泽西司法部长
So long as you're not the Attorney General of New Jersey.
鸡肉你几乎没动
You hardly touched your chicken.
我吃好了
I'm okay.
威尔 我为你感到骄傲 我们都是
I'm proud of you,Will. We all are.
你爸爸也会的
Your dad would be,too.
关上门
Shut the door.
-七  -六
-Seven. -Six.
四十二
42.
-一  -六十四
-One. -64.
-十四  -七十二
-14. -72.
-四十二  -七十一
-42. -71.
七十九
79.
米勒 你去哪了
Mueller,where you been?
在密歇根出了意外
There was an accident on Michigan.
你带来了什么"午餐"
What did you bring for lunch?
"卷心菜"
Cabbage.
小心 佛瑞德
Watch it,Fred.
可能有蟑螂 准备好拍死它
There might be a cockroach ready to pounce.
一点都不好笑 到处都是臭虫
That's not funny. There's bugs everywhere.
-四十二  -十四
-42. - 14.
-七十二  -九
-72. -Nine.
两个胖夫人(丰厚之意) 八十八
Two fat ladies,88.
最后 朋友们
In closing,my friends,
改变世界不能谦顺的绵羊 要靠战士
it's not the meek who change the world,but the fighters,
信仰者
the believers.
芝加哥现在面临险境
The city of Chicago is at a great precipice,
摇摆在善恶边缘
teetering on the brink between good and evil.
我在此起誓 与卡彭(美国黑手党老大)暴徒斗争到底
So I vow to fight the Capone mob,
不退出 不逃避
not bow out,not walk away,
不投降 不放弃 战斗到底
not give in, not give up,but fight.
为了天下父母
Fight to win for the fathers, the mothers,
为了这座城市的学童
and the schoolchildren of this city.
但内斯先生 您将从何处着手
Yeah,but,Mr. Ness, how are you gonna go about this?
如果有人说反抗根本不是办法
And if anyone says that to fight doesn't get you anywhere,
财政部探员单枪匹马 根本毫无作用
that a lone treasury agent can't make a difference,
卡彭一伙太过强大
that the Capone machine is too powerful,
那是因为他们不了解艾略特 内斯
then I say they don't know Eliot Ness.
-谁  -我是威尔逊
-Who is it? -It's Wilson.
-有进展吗  -是的 先生
-Making progress? -Yes,sir.
钻石皮带扣一万四
14,000 in diamond belt buckles.
员工圣诞礼物
Christmas gifts for his employees.
而我只有差劲的香槟一瓶
All I got was a lousy bottle of champagne.
休伦的妓院
The cathouse on Huron.
早上交给我完整解析报告
I'd like a full breakdown by morning.
先生
Se?or
汤普森先生 他找你
Mr. Thompson, he wants you.
渴吗
Thirsty?
说实话 是紧张
Nervous,speaking frankly.
只是在公共场合叙叙旧而已
Just a friendly conversation in a very public place.
邀请方式让我很慌乱
It was the invitation got me rattled.
不要管他 他很听话
Don't mind him. He's a pussycat.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
告诉我是谁坏了我的假期
How about you tell me who it was spoiled my vacation?
光是跟你说话我就可能被杀掉
You know I could get killed for just talking to you.
你不说也是死
And you will be if you don't.
是兰斯基和卢西亚诺
It was Lansky and Luciano.
他们在等待机会 让马拉暂罗觉得他才是王
They're gonna bide their time, let Maranzano think he's king.
只要有足够拥护者...
Then the minute they got enough support...
他的统治就会结束
His reign is over.
他们也会杀了我 我知道
They're gonna take me out,too. I fucking know it.
他们一旦成功 就会给我背后来一刀
Put the knife in my back the second they get the chance.
但你入了马塞里亚一伙
But you were on board with the Masseria hit.
我别无选择 要么赞成要么死
What choice did I have? It was go along or else.
马拉暂罗对你没意见
Maranzano's got no beef with you.
对他而言 大西洋城是你的
As far as he's concerned, Atlantic City's yours.
我只要守住已有的即可
I can keep what's already mine?
多么慷慨
How exceedingly generous.
比另外两个慷慨多了
A lot more so than the other two.
马拉暂罗知道他们的计划吗
Does Maranzano know what they're planning?
如果他知道 早就阻止了
If he does,he ain't letting on.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do it?
和不能信任的人一起共事
Work with people you can't trust?
这是工作邀请吗
Is that an offer?
如果是呢
If it were?
汤普森先生 我发誓 赴汤蹈火
Anything,Mr. Thompson, I swear.
我可以立马为你效劳
I'd come work for you in a heartbeat.
告诉我的人 兰斯基在哪
Tell my man where we can find Lansky.
早上来见我
In the morning,come see me.
谢谢你 汤普森先生 一定办到
Thank you,Mr. Thompson. I will.
谢谢 先生
Thank you,sir.
比利 肯特是个可爱的女孩
She was a lovely girl,Billie Kent.
上帝怜悯
God of all mercies,
一切皆有天意
You make nothing in vain,
您爱着您的子民
and You love all that You have made.
安抚我们的悲伤
Comfort us in our grief
您永不止息的爱
and console us with the knowledge
慰藉着我们
of Your unfailing love.
我主耶稣在上
Through Jesus Christ,our Lord.
阿门
Amen.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
做好选择 明白吗
Made your choice,then,eh?
先生
Sir?
你的老板 那个海军准将
Your boss there,the Commodore.
他说会好好埋葬她的
He said he would bury her proper.
死人还要钱有啥用
Money never did the dead no good.
填上土
Fill it in.
不 不要
No. No.
现在回到最受美国欢迎的家庭
And now we're back with America's favorite family.
搞什么 慢点
Ooh! What the deuce? Slow down.
妈妈的新花瓶
Mother's new vase.
贝琪 亲爱的 我告诉过你
Betsy,dear,I told you
不能在屋里玩滑轮
there will be no roller-skating inside the house.
我记不住
Well,I don't remember that.
我都说了100遍了
I said it 100 times.
这就是你的问题了 爸爸
Well,there's your problem,Daddy.
我还数不到那么多
I can't count that high.
-外公  -你好 小孩
-Hey,Pop. -Hello,Junior.
我曾想借福特车钥匙
Say,I was hoping to borrow the keys to the Ford.
当然可以
Why,certainly.
你是说 我可以用车了
You mean,I can really take the car?
什么车 我是说你可以借钥匙
What car? I said you could borrow the keys.
你不是还在生我的气吧 是吗外公
Gee,you're not still sore at me,are you,Pop?
我为什么要生气
Now why on earth would I be sore?
因为我弄坏了挡泥板
On account I dented the fender?
-真的吗  -没有 现在感觉好点了吗
-You did? -No,but don't you feel better now?
-红的是我的  -不 是我的
-I'm red. -No,I'm red.
-红的是我的  -这就开始了
-I'm red. -Started already right over here.
-不 红的是我的  -红的是我的
-No,I'm red. -I'm red.
别碰它
Don't touch.
-给我  -女士们 女士们
-Give me that back. -Ladies. Ladies.
-红的是我的  -抱歉
-I'm red. -Sorry.
-没事  -对不起
-Okay. -I'm sorry.
你确定我们要这么做吗
Are you sure we should be doing this?
这里我是老大
I say what goes here.
明白我的意思吗
Understand?
你身材不错
You have a lovely figure.
新年前夜
New Year's Eve.
我在怡东酒店穿着这件衣服
I wore this at the Hotel Excelsior.
保罗 惠特曼(爵士之王)在演奏
Paul Whiteman played.
漂亮吗
Does it flatter me?
需要裁一下
Some tailoring,perhaps.
底边低点
Lower the hemline.
能拿点好的文具吗
Could you not get proper stationery?
这样已经很冒险了
I'm risking my job as it is.
现在不能再瞎写信给总统了
No crazy letters to the president,now.
你怎么会这么想
Why would you think I would do that?
因为你在精神病院 亲爱的
'Cause you're in the booby hatch,honey.
所以不能用纸笔
That's why no pen and paper is allowed.
我清楚自己做了些错事
I did something wrong. I know that.
但医生说我需要好好照顾
But the doctor said I needed to be looked after.
我只是...一切太混乱了
I just... it's all a jumble.
我只是...
I just...
需要理清自己的思路
I need to get my thoughts straight.
用软木塞把朗姆酒塞紧了
Make sure you cork the rum.
有人在里面看到过果蝇...
Fella found a fruit fly...
-救命啊  -天呐
-Oh,help! -Oh,my God!
他倒下了
He's going down there!
一辆黑色的别克干的
It's the black one. The Buick.
找到那辆车 找到那辆车
Get the car. Get the car!
-别让她呆在这  -好的 咱们走吧
-Take her out of here. -All right,come on,let's go.
转过来 咱走吧
Turn around. Let's go.
-各位女士  -快点离开这
-Hey,ladies,come on. -Come on,get out of here.
哈瓦那明信片